Guide to the Poster Collection Documenting Yale
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Poster collection documenting Yale
1717-2016
RU 185
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
260.83
(88 boxes)
The collection consists of posters that document all aspects of Yale student and community life including clubs, organizations, film societies, concerts, lectures, theater, class announcements, commencements, and reunions.
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 48-A (YRG 48-A), Yale pictorial records and collections.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of posters that document all aspects of Yale student and community life including clubs, organizations, film societies, concerts, lectures, theater, class announcements, commencements, and reunions.
Arrangement
The posters are arranged alphabetically by subject and by subsequent accessions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
"Iconoclast" poster gift of David Alan Richards, 2013. Indian Neck Folk Music Festival posters gift of Mrs. Celeste Hemingson, 2013.
Posters; Yale University -- Societies, etc.; Yale University -- Students
- Posters, 1717-1998; Series I
  - Advertisements, General (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Announcements and Notices, 1865-1960s (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
    - The Iconoclast sales poster, 1873 (Box 1A, Folder 1)
  - Art classes, programs etc. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Athletics
    - General, Circa 1890-1950s (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Crew, 1862- (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Clubs, Societies & Organizations
    - Brothers in Unity, Circa 1850s-1880s (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Linonia, 1851-1958 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Russian club (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous, 1869-1960s (Box 2, Folder 10-13)
  - Commencement & Alumni
    - Exercises, 1807-1890s (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - 1900-1960s (Box 2, Folder 15-16)
  - Concerts
    - Instrumental, 1868-1992 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
    - Instrumental, 1868-1992 (Box 3, Folder 19-23)
    - Instrumental, 1868-1992 (Box 4, Folder 24-25)
    - Instrumental, Chamber Music, 1940s-1950s (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Vocal, 1868-1963 (Box 4, Folder 27-28)
    - Vocal, 1868-1978 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Vocal Bach Cantata, 1940s (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Dance, Mixers & Proms, 1868-1979 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Drama
    - College Dramats, 1959-1963 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Dramat, 1960s-1979, undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Playbills, 1903-1940 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - School of Drama, 1959-1979 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Miscellaneous theater posters, 1961-2012, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Exhibitions
    - General, 1947-1979 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Library, 1951-1955 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Yale University Art Gallery, 1870s 1950s (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Film Society
    - Berkeley-Davenport Film Society, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - "Boola Boola...Yale Goes Coed" a documentaary by Julie Pimsleur, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 40A)
    - Ezra Stiles Film Society, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Films Anonymous, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Films, Spider, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - The Prisoner, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Things that go bump in the night, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Yale Law School Film Society, 1979 (Box 6, Folder 46-47)
    - Yale Film Society, 1979, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 48-49)
  - Film Miscellaneous, 1952- (Box 6, Folder 50-51)
  - Graduate School General, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Lectures
    - General, 1876-1998 (Box 7, Folder 53-54)
    - General, 1901-1960s (Box 7, Folder 55-58)
    - General, 1901-1960s (Box 8, Folder 59-60)
    - Arts, 1947-1955, undated (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - Education, 1943-1959 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - Law, 1951-1959, undated (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - Political Science, 1902-1962, undated (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - Religious, 1902-1960s (Box 9, Folder 65-66)
    - Science, Circa 1930's-1950s (Box 9, Folder 67)
    - Sheffield Scientific School, 1897-1903 (Box 9, Folder 68-69)
  - Medical Announcements & Advertisements, 1919-1953 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Publications
    - Yale Pageant, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 71)
    - General, 1871-1913, undated (Box 9, Folder 72)
    - Yale Literary Magazine, 1868-1872 (Box 9, Folder 73-74)
  - Radio W1YU, WTIC, WYBC, 1947-1958 (Box 10, Folder 75)
  - Reunions, 1929-1958 (Box 10, Folder 76)
  - Rules and Regulations, 1860s-1914 (Box 10, Folder 77)
  - Sixties (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - Student Life
    - General, 1867-1931 (Box 10, Folder 79)
    - General, 1920s-1960s (Box 10, Folder 80)
    - Bookstores, 1845-1977 (Box 10, Folder 81)
    - Civil Rights, 1964 (Box 10, Folder 82)
    - Debates, 1930s-1950s (Box 10, Folder 83)
    - Library Notices, 1868-1940s (Box 10, Folder 84)
    - Protests, Undated (Box 10, Folder 85)
    - Religious Services, 1940s-1950s (Box 10, Folder 86)
    - Residential Information, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 87)
    - War, 1940, undated (Box 11, Folder 88)
  - Summer Programs, 1935, 1963 (Box 11, Folder 89)
  - Yale in China, 1929-1952, undated (Box 11, Folder 90)
  - Yale Publications, 1860-1961, undated (Box 11, Folder 91-92)
  - Yale University Club, Circa 1940s (Box 11, Folder 93)
- Posters [folio], 1717–2006; Series II
  - Art and Architecture, programs (Box 12)
  - Athletics
    - General, 1900–2004 (Box 13)
    - Baseball, 1870–1903 (Box 14)
    - Baseball, 1870–1903 (Box 15)
    - Crew, 1852–1900 (Box 16)
    - Crew, 1900–1999 (Box 17)
    - Football, 1880–1900 (Box 18)
    - Football, 1901- (Box 19)
    - Track, 1900- (Box 20)
  - Certificate and Honors, 1718–1904 (Box 21)
  - Clubs, Societies and Corporations
    - Miscellaneous, 1807–1869 (Box 22)
    - Yale Friends of Turkey, 2006 (Box 23)
  - Commencement, 1869–1908 (Box 24)
  - Concerts and Programs
    - 1950–1979 (Box 25)
    - 1978–1983 (Box 26)
  - Dance, Mixers and Proms, 1937–1979 (Box 27)
  - Drama
    - College Dramats (Box 28)
    - Dramat, 1900–1937 (Box 29)
    - Dramat, 1937 (Box 30)
    - Playbills, 1900- (Box 31)
    - Yale Repertory Theatre, 1970- (Box 32)
    - School of Drama, 1936–1962, undated (Box 33)
    - Miscellaneous Theater, 1903–1956 (Box 34)
  - Exhibitions
    - Galleries, 1921, 1984, 1999 (Box 35)
    - General, Circa 1960s-1970 (Box 36)
    - Library, 1921-1990s (Box 37)
    - Yale School of Fine Arts, Circa 1890–1997 (Box 38)
    - School of Art and Architecture, 1998- (Box 39)
  - Film
    - General (Box 40)
    - Yale Film Society (Box 41)
    - Medical Film Societies, 1990- (Box 42)
    - Graduate School, Undated (Box 43)
  - Lectures
    - General, 1917–1959 (Box 44)
    - General, 1960–1981 (Box 45)
    - Yale Law School, 1911 (Box 46)
    - Medical School, 1911 (Box 47)
    - Sheffield Scientific School, 1877 (Box 48)
    - Meeting Fellowships, 1917- (Box 49)
    - Military, Yale in, 1916–1940 (Box 50)
    - Poetry Readings, 1933–1949 (Box 51)
  - Publications
    - Yale Banner, 1883-1953 (Box 52)
    - Harpy -first Yale-Harvard-Princeton Magazine (project) (Box 53)
    - Catalogue of Faculty and Students, 1799–1816 (Box 54)
    - The College Courant (Box 55)
    - The Yale Courant, 1913 (Box 56)
    - The Yale Daily News, 1934–1955 (Box 57)
    - The Yale Illustrated Horoscope, Circa 1880 (Box 57)
    - Yale Literary Chronicles (Box 58)
    - Yale Literary Magazine, 1868–1948 (Box 59)
    - Yale Record, 1892–1954 (Box 60)
    - Yale Scientific Magazine, 1951 (Box 61)
  - Radio, WYBC, 1946-1950 (Box 62)
  - Reunions
    - General, 1870–1900 (Box 63)
    - General, 1901- (Box 64)
    - Reunion posters and placards, Classes of, 1853–1907 (Box 65)
    - Alumni Dinner (Box 66)
  - Rules and Regulations (Box 67)
  - Seminars, Institutes, 1985–1989 (Box 68)
  - Singing Groups
    - Orchestras, 1950, 1980-1982 (Box 69)
    - Circa 1880–1950 (Box 70)
  - Special Events and Celebrations
    - Yale Bicentennial, 1901 (Box 71)
    - Yale Pageant, 1916 (Box 72)
    - Special Olympics World Games, Connecticut, 1995 (Box 73)
    - Two posters and two programs from the awards ceremony of the 2013 Donald Windham - Sandy M. Campbell Literary Prizes. (Box 73)
  - Student Life
    - General, 1908–1949 (Box 74)
    - Bookstore (Box 75)
    - Furniture Sales (Box 76)
    - Songs (Box 77)
    - Yale Banner, 1953 (Box 78)
  - Yale in Magazines, 1895–1996 (Box 79)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 80)
  - Lipstick Ascending on Caterpillar Track, gift to Yale University, Claes Oldenburg, 1969 May (Box 81)
- Poster of Yale Varsity Athletes, 2004; Accession 2006-A-074; 2.5; (1 folio) (Box 1)
- Facsimile reproduction of the Yale College Charter of 1745, Accession 1990-A-088 (Box 2)
- Posters for the School of Art and the Norfolk Summer School, 2000-2003; Accession 2005-A-030
  - Posters for the School of Art and the Norfok Summer School, 2000-2003 (Box 1)
- Poster from Norfolk School of Art, 2004; Accession 2006-A-076
  - Poster from Norfolk School of Art, 2004 (Folder 1)
- Posters of the Yale Law School Tercentennial Lecture Series, 2001; Accession 2006-A-183
  - Tercentennial Lecture Series posters, 2001 (Box 1)
- Posters advertising the Indian Neck Folk Festival, Circa 1960; Accession 2014-A-030
  - Bonnie Dobson, The New Lost City Ramblers, and Jackie Washington, 1957 [?] November 2 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Reverend Gary Davis, 1958[?] April 12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Jim Kweskin, 1958[?] October 12 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Hal Holbrook in "Mark Twain Tonight", 1961[?] December 2 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Joan Baez and Pete Seeger, 1962[?] November 17 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Posters advertising the Terror on Tape event, 2016-05-06-2016-05-07; Accession 2016-A-078
  - Fliers advertising the Terror on Tape event, 2016-05-06-2016-05-07 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Poster advertising the Terror on Tape event, 2016-05-06-2016-05-07 (Box 1, Folder 1)